Hello everyone, and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
And I am Katherine, and today we
have a fun game focused lesson for you.
That's right. Today
we have an elementary
lesson, and it's all about
playing board games.
Okay, and the game in today's lesson
is a famous one. It's called Monopoly.
Monopoly.
I don't know if you have
this in your countries.
It's a game in which
you try to earn money.
And sell property, and buy property. That
means hotels, houses, things like that.
Right.
And it's very famous. We're going
to learn more about this game
today, so let's take a listen to
our dialogue for the first time.
Everyone knows that.
Well, you can't
just take the money.
You have to ask the bank
for money, and I'm the banker.
Bank up?
Yes.
Can I have my $200 please?
Sure. Here you are. $200.
Thank you, please come again.
Now it's my turn to roll the dice.
All right, we're back, so we saw
some very interesting words there.
The dialogue is two people
playing, so when we take a
look at some of those words,
use it in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
This first word we can
hear when we play games,
it's not a good thing to
be, but it's very common.
The word is cheater.
A cheater. All right, and that's a noun.
A person that is a cheater.
If somebody says you are a
cheater, what does that mean?
This means the person
is not honest at games.
For example, Marco, you and
I are playing a card game, and
you go to the bathroom, and
then I take the cards I want.
I hide the cards I don't want.
That's called cheating.
Right.
Okay, the verb to cheat, but here
a person who cheats is a cheater.
Okay.
You're a cheater. He's a cheater.
All right, and remember
that you say cheater, right?
Because sometimes many people that are
learning English would say you are a cheater.
Right.
A cheater here is the noun. That means
it's the name of the person who does this.
He is a cheater. They are cheaters.
Okay.
And while moving on, sometimes cheaters and
people that steal things are sent to jail.
That's right. So maybe if you go
to a casino and you cheat, you use
a cell phone or you use some kind
of a computer device to win money.
This is called cheating, and
the casino will send you to jail.
All right. So jail is the
place where people go.
What's the difference
between prison and jail?
Basically, they're the same thing.
Okay.
So two words for the same
thing. People who break
the law, people who
do bad things go to jail.
Not just cheaters.
All right. So now you have another word.
Maybe you've seen that show prison break.
And so jail is pretty much the same thing.
So the show could have
been called jailbreak.
That's right. But yeah.
All right. So moving on
our third word is the person
who's handling money
says, well, you know what?
I'm the banker, a banker.
So you know already
banker is probably a person.
This is a job.
So a banker is a person
who works at a bank.
Okay. So, but what about the person
that helps you when you go to the bank?
Like when that gives
you the money and the
bank teller is not the
same as a banker, right?
No. Generally speaking, a person who
gives you money and collects your money.
This is a teller, a bank teller.
A bank teller. But a banker
is someone who works in the
bank to make big decisions,
to invest money, to give loans.
Okay. So usually maybe
managers or executives are bankers.
That's right. Okay. And
moving on to our last
word here, we have a
verb and that is to collect.
Right. So in the conversation
between these two people,
Karen, the woman says, when
you pass go, you collect $200.
Okay. So to collect means to get.
That's right. To get or to take.
So at the end of every month, my
landlord comes to my house to collect rent.
That means to take money from
me for the house or the apartment.
Okay. Good. So it's, yeah, now you have
another way to say to get or to acquire.
That's right. All right.
So very interesting.
Why don't we go back,
listen to this dialogue again.
And we'll take a look at all of
these words that we just saw.
And when we return, we'll
take a look at some phrases.
Hey, why did you take that money? You are
such a cheater. I should send you to jail.
I am not cheating.
When you pass go, you collect $200.
Everyone knows that. Well,
you can't just take the money.
You have to ask the bank
for money. And I'm the banker.
Banker? Yes. Can I have my $200, please?
Sure. Here you are.
$200. Thank you.
Please come again. Now
it's my turn to rule the dice.
All right. We're back.
So now let's take a
look at three key
phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Marco, you're such a cheater.
Such a cheater. I'm not
a cheater. But what, what
do you mean when you
say you are such a cheater?
It's a little cheater, right?
That's what you could say
this for many different things.
You're such a liar. You are such
a, hmm, such a terrible person.
It's such a bad person. Right.
Normally we say this when we want to
criticize someone, when we want
to say something mean or negative.
You're such a means you're really a
bad person. You're really a cheater. Right.
So obviously because we are using a
noun, we can't really use an adverb, right?
If you're saying an adjective
like, I am very happy.
You can't say you
are very cheater.
No, no, you wouldn't say
that you have to get used
a different sentence
structure to give emphasis.
So in this case, you
could say cheater.
Right. Okay, but that's
not as strong as it.
As such a cheater.
You are such a cheater.
That means, gosh, you're a
really big cheater. Right. Exactly.
So this is the way that you
would use that structure such
a and then a noun that is
describing this person, right?
You could also use it for positive
statements like you're such a good friend.
Very good. So then you are using the
adjective, you are such a good friend.
You're such a nice person.
Okay. Excellent. All right.
So moving on, we
saw another interesting
phrase when he said,
you will, you know what?
You can't just take the money. So what
does it mean when he says, can't just?
Okay, we could say you
can't take the money.
This is basically a rule.
You can't take the money.
But you can't just take
the money means there are
other things you have to do
before you take the money.
Okay. You have to, in this
case, ask the banker for
the money or for example,
if I want to drive a car.
I can't just go buy a
car. I need to first get a
driver's license. I need
to learn how to drive.
I need to register. So you
can't just just hear means
there's some things we need
to do before this happens.
Right. You can't just means you
can't do these things that easily.
You have to do other
things before it, as you said.
Exactly. Okay. So very interesting.
We'll try to use that one in a sentence.
But moving on to our last phrase
when the person said, you know what?
All right. You want your $200.
Here you are. Here you are.
So sometimes people think that
this phrase means you are here.
Right. Which it could in
some cases. Yeah, that's right.
So basically you're saying,
I found you. Here you are.
I found you. But in this
case, this doesn't make sense.
We're talking about money.
We're talking about a game.
So if you think about
this, here you are, you can
imagine someone is
giving someone else a thing.
So in the case of the
bank, teller member
we're talking about
getting money at a bank.
A bank teller might
say, here you are, sir,
here's your money and
then give you some money.
So this is something we say in English
when we give something to someone else.
Right. Because otherwise, I
guess it's strange if you just,
you know, give something to
someone and you don't say anything.
Right. You need to say something.
And if you say here, that's very rude.
Yeah. So this is a polite way to
say, please take this. This is for you.
There you go. You might
hear this at the restaurant.
Here you are. Here's your
food. Here you are. Right.
Okay. It's a very useful
phrase. And so I think
it's time for us to listen
to this dialogue again.
And we'll be back to
talk a little bit more.
Hey, why did you take that money? You are
such a cheater. I should send you to jail.
I'm not cheating. When you pass go,
you collect $200. Everyone knows that.
Well, you can't
just take the money.
You have to ask the bank
for money and I'm the banker.
Banker? Yes. Can I have my $200, please?
Sure. Here you are. $200.
Thank you. Please come again.
Now it's my turn to roll the dice.
All right. We're back.
So a lot of interesting words.
There are a lot of interesting phrases.
They're really interesting and very useful.
So remember to try and
use such a, you can't just, or
here you are when you're
giving something to someone.
That's right. These are really great.
And I recommend also playing some games.
These are great ways to improve
your language skills. I'm monopoly.
The game that they're
playing in this dialogue
is a really fun one
for numbers, right?
Because the whole point of
the game, the whole purpose
of the game is to make the
most money of anyone playing.
And this is a really fun one
because you get to buy houses
and hotels and there's simple
street names and place names.
Like Park Avenue or the
boardwalk. So you'll learn a lot
of really great things about
American culture and English.
Yeah. It's a really good game, very
popular. I'm sure they have it in your
language, but if you could get it in
English, that would be really great.
And also another really
good game to play with
your friends to practice
your vocab is Scrabble.
Scrabble, that's hard.
Scrabble is a game about words.
And so basically you have to make
words out of letters and whoever
has the most interesting words,
unique words that person wins.
So obviously it's a great game to
improve your vocab because you also
learn some words that maybe you
didn't know before in your friends' new.
So it's really fun to play.
Obviously don't play with
any native English speakers
because they might win.
But it's a really cool game to
play if you have any friends who
are also learning English. You
can get together, place Scrabble.
And it's a fun way to improve your vocab
and to also fight a little bit because
all the time some people are trying to
make up new words that don't really exist.
We call them cheaters. Cheaters.
So yeah, let us know about
your game experiences.
Do you like to play games?
Do you have a favorite game?
Practice some of these
and let us know how they go.
All right. We'll see you guys there.
EnglishPod.com. Bye, everyone.
[music]